田納西州
納什維爾
♪ 童心未泯 ♪
♪ Never get too big ♪
♪ 也不曾有過包袱 ♪
♪ Never get too heavy ♪
♪ 但不覺得自己有多酷 ♪
♪ You never get too cool ♪
♪ 沒法付清債務了 ♪
♪ You stop paying your dues ♪
♪ 身無長物的男孩有什麼用處 ♪
♪ What can a poor boy do? ♪
♪ 最好還是投奔親媽吧 ♪
♪ Better go back to your mama ♪
♪ 她會好好照料你 ♪
♪ Oh, she'll take care of you ♪
我真沒想到早上起來看到的第一件事
Christ, I'll no' miss that country
就是這麼一大包要帶到鄉村的垃圾
rubbish first thing in the morning.
你還是會想我的對吧
I bet you'll miss me though, eh?
我才沒空想你
I hope I get the chance to.
♪ 熬夜買醉直到黎明破曉 ♪
♪ Stay out drinking Till the morning comes ♪
♪ 身無長物的男孩有什麼用處 ♪
♪ What can a poor boy do? ♪
請簽一下名
Autograph, please.
你就是下一個多麗·帕頓
You're gonna be the next Dolly Parton!
多麗·帕頓  美國著名鄉村音樂女歌手
一定加油啊
Go on, yourself!
加油  加油  加油
Cheerio! Cheerio! Cheerio!
我他媽一定會的
Fuck! Oh, yeah!
♪ 鄉村女孩 ♪
♪ Country girl ♪
♪ 握住我的手 ♪
♪ Take my hand ♪
♪ 帶我離開這一片荒蕪之地 ♪
♪ Lead me through this diseased land... ♪
請不要移動腳部
Can you keep your foot still, please?
我已經上訴了  很快就不用它了
I've appealed it, so it'll be off before it's on.
當它在啟動狀態時  從晚上七點
Well, while it's on, you cannot leave the registered address
到次日早上七點  都不能離開登記範圍
after 7.00 at night until 7.00 the next morning.
那還是我麼
Is that me?
♪ 要一直堅持下來 ♪
♪ Got to keep on keeping on ♪
真倒霉
Fuck's sake!
♪ 瘋女人擾亂了你的心 ♪
♪ Crazy women mess your head ♪
♪ 起床仍未醒酒  血流在陌生的床上 ♪
♪ Wake up drunk and bleeding In some strange bed ♪
♪ 身無長物的男孩有什麼用處 ♪
♪ What can a poor boy do? ♪
別再回來了啊
And don't come back!
♪ 最好還是回去投奔親娘 ♪
♪ You better go back to your mama ♪
♪ 她會照料好你 ♪
♪ Oh, she'll take care of you ♪
♪ 鄉村女孩啊 ♪
♪ Oh, country girl ♪
格拉斯哥
♪ 握住我的手 ♪
♪ Take my hand ♪
♪ 帶我離開這荒涼之地 ♪
♪ Lead me through this diseased land ♪
♪ 我身心疲憊 ♪
♪ I am tired, I am weak ♪
♪ 精疲力竭 ♪
♪ I am worn ♪
♪ 我曾偷竊  罪加己身 ♪
♪ I have stole, I have sinned ♪
♪ 靈魂已沾染污垢 ♪
♪ Oh, my soul is unclean ♪
♪ 你得一直堅持下去 ♪
♪ Country girl got to keep on keeping on ♪
♪ 鄉村女孩 ♪
♪ Country girl ♪
♪ 你得一直堅持下去 ♪
♪ Got to keep on keeping on ♪
野玫瑰
♪ 我出門散步 ♪
♪ I go out walking ♪
♪ 沐浴午夜月光 ♪
♪ After midnight out in the moonlight ♪
♪ 就像我們曾經一起做的 ♪
♪ Just like we used to do ♪
♪ 我總是在前進 ♪
♪ I'm always walking... ♪
他還在洗澡
He's in his bath.
你好  蘿絲琳
Hello, Rose Lynn.
可以來杯茶麼  你最近怎麼樣
Would you like a cup of tea? How are you?
♪ 我總是午夜之後散步 ♪
♪ I'm always walking after midnight ♪
♪ 只為找尋你的蹤跡 ♪
♪ Searching for you ♪
老天爺  你遮遮羞吧
Cover yourself, for God's sake!
遮遮羞
Cover yourself!
我去
Oh, fuck, yeah!
一路從蘇格蘭的格拉斯哥到劇院
All the way from Glasgow, Scotland,
請歡迎一個新人歌手
please welcome a little girl by the name of Rose Lynn Harlan
蘿絲琳·哈倫
to the Opry.
女士們  先生們  羅斯·林·哈蘭
Rose Lynn Harlan, ladies and gentlemen,
第一次在納什維爾的田納西州表演
performing for the first time here in Nashville, Tennessee.
太棒了  去你的
Whoo! Fuckin'A.
好吧  過會兒再來看你
Right, I'll see you.
什麼時候
When?
媽媽
Mum!
你好呀
Oh, hi.
進來吧  小林
Come on, Lyle. Come on.
你要去哪裏  是要去吃魚嗎
Where do you think you're going, all done up like a fish supper?
天哪  他讓你失望了  肯定的
Christ, he's got you down, so he has.
真可怕  千萬別這樣
That's scary. Don't do that.
無論如何  我哪兒也不去
Anyway, I'm not going anywhere.
我和你們一起吃晚飯
I'm having my dinner wi' yous.
他那麼話嘮  你卻沉默寡言
He never shuts up, you never speak.
怎麼了  你這麼沉默
What's going on in there, eh? Sponsored silence?
你想我嗎
Did you miss me, eh? Hmm?
蘿絲琳
Rose Lynn?
我還以為是你媽媽呢
I thought you were your mum there.
一年就這麼過去了  時間不等人
That cannae have been 12 month. The time's went in like that.
是啊
Aye.
你好  瑪麗昂
Hello, Marion!
你們倆都晚安
Night, both of you.
她挺漂亮  阿曼達
She looks good. Amanda.
當然了  她在這上面花了不少時間
Aye. So she should. Enough time at it.
她還躺在錫紙上嗎  是的
Does she still lie out here on tin foil? Oh, aye.
她穿著比基尼曬日光浴
One peek of the sun and that one's in a bikini.
前幾天她吃我的黃油  你的黃油
Other day she was in after my butter. Your butter?
身上到處都是  這很正常  瑪麗昂
Puts it all over her. It's natural, Marion.
如果你是個面包捲  那就再正常不過了
Aye, natural if you're a roll.
瑪麗今晚本來要過來看你
Mary was gonna come tonight to see you,
但是她的關節炎很嚴重  所以
but she's awful bad with her arthritis, so...
真可惜  是的
Oh, that's a shame. Aye.
她膝蓋有炎癥  只得退休了
It's in her knees now so that's her had to retire.
其實
It's, uh...
你可以在節假日工作  時薪八磅
Eight pound an hour, holidays.
她說可以幫幫我的忙  也帶你去
Says she'll see you into it as a favour to me.
當清潔工是嗎  是的  挺好
Cleaning, aye? Aye, very good.
怎麼了  你在想什麼
Why, what were you thinking?
我沒在想什麼
Thinking? No.
我什麼也沒想  我出門在外你不擔心嗎
I wasnae thinking. I've just got out. Don't you worry about me.
不擔心  我在想你的孩子
No, I wasnae. I was thinking about your kids.
我要去納什維爾
I'm going to Nashville.
你最好小心一點
Well, you better mind your tag doesnae
通過安檢的時候別露餡
go off when you're going through security.
首先  我要去劇院  把工作拿回來
First thing I'm going down the Opry I'm gonna get my job back
我會努力的
and I'm gonna work for it.
我不屬於這裏的
There's nothing for me here.
在那裏我可以磨練手藝
There I can be honing my craft,
每天晚上在外面肆無忌憚地傻笑
out gigging every night.
磨練手藝
Honing your cra...?
你為那個白日夢付出的代價還不夠嗎
Do you not think you've sacrificed enough for that fantasy?
我們做出的犧牲還不夠嗎
Have we all not sacrificed enough?
怎麼就是白日夢了
How's it a fantasy?
這是我唯一擅長的  學做生意
It's the only thing I'm good at. Learn a trade.
上大學  你沒在聽
Go to college. You're not listening.
我不管你做什麼  但你得搞點正事
I don't care what you do, but do something.
我會好好利用我的天賦的
I've got my talent and I'm gonna use that.
你沒看電視嗎
Have you not been watching telly?
他們根本不缺會唱歌的人
There's no shortage of folk who can sing.
當他們飛過水面回家時有一支
...a high, distinctive whistle
離地面很高的獨特的哨子
as they fly home over the water.
我的天啊
Fuck's sake!
♪ 請原諒 ♪
♪ I beg your pardon ♪
開始吧  踏步  旋轉
Here we go. Step and swivel.
背靠背  向外  向內
Back to back, out, in.
♪ 我不曾承諾你一個 ♪
♪ I never promised you a rose garden ♪
♪ 灑滿陽光的玫瑰花園 ♪
♪ Along with the sunshine ♪
轉過來
Turn.
桑德拉  注意腳的動作
Come on, Sandra. Watch your feet!
獨行俠騎馬進城了
Oh, the Lone Ranger rides into town.
婕基  給我來杯啤酒可以嗎
Do you wanna get me a wee beer, Jackie?
看著我  別盯著旁邊的人看
Watch me! Don't watch your neighbour!
看著我  別盯別人
Eyes on me, no' your neighbour!
我錯過了什麼
So, what have I missed?
以前這兒有老鼠嗎
Was there mice before?
是的  好吧
Aye. Well, then,
太陽底下無新事
there's nothing new under the sun.
我聽說你被盯上了
I hear you're on the tag.
卡納在這裏放屁了吧
Cannae fart round here.
是的  但我已經力爭上訴了
Aye, I am, but I've appealed it, so
幾周後  我會是嶄新的我
a couple of weeks I'll be brandnew.
星期五和星期六的生意都很好
Fridays and Saturdays, boom.
那兩天我們有密西西比冰原
Fridays and Saturdays we've got Mississippi Tundra.
誰
Who?
天哪  你一定很絕望
Christ, yous must be desperate!
沒人想看見一個真罪犯四處晃蕩
Nobody wants to see a convicted criminal up there.
人們來這裏是為了逃避那些破事的
Folk come here to get away from all that.
約翰尼·卡什才是個真罪犯  混蛋
Johnny Cash was a convicted criminal, you bawbag.
回到你的捉蟲崗位上吧
Anyway, away back to your mousetraps.
我需要這份工作  婕基
I need this job, Jackie,
那他媽是我的樂隊
and it's my fucking band.
那是家庭樂隊  你別自欺欺人了
It's the house band. You're your own worst enemy, you.
我不同意  勝負未定呢
I wouldnae agree. There's strong competition.
去你媽的  滾開傻逼
Fuck you! Fuck off! Fucking stupid cow!
你搶了我的工作唄  放開我
You nicked my job, did you? Get off! Get off me!
把手拿開  滾出去
Get your hands off me! Get out.
我在這裏工作了十年
Ten year I've been working here.
你是上定黑名單了
Right, you're barred.
滾  媽的連客人都沒有的俱樂部
Get out! Fucking nofuckinghopers' clubhouse!
你就是個禽獸
You're an animal. An animal!
去你媽的
Fuck!
沒想到你早上會過來
Didn't know you were on mornings.
你家小姑娘怎麼樣  明天再說吧
How's your lassie? Oh, ask me tomorrow.
他住在房子底層
He lives in the bottom half of the house.
樓上還有一所房子
There's another house up the stair.
我朋友安迪住在那裏
My mate Andy lives there.
然後他們買了隔壁的房子
And then they bought the house next door.
勞倫住在隔壁  那有一個小陽台
Lauren lives next door with a wee balcony.
♪ 我一直不合時宜地生活在孟菲斯 ♪
♪ I've been living on the wrong side of Memphis ♪
♪ 這次我真的要離開了 ♪
♪ I'm really breaking away this time ♪
♪ 毒氣坦克和69年風暴潮 ♪
♪ A full tank of gas and a '69 Tempest ♪
♪ 帶我去納什維爾吧 ♪
♪ Taking me to that Nashville sign ♪
♪ 事已至此  無法回頭 ♪
♪ No turning back, I've come too far ♪
♪ 帶著我的舊吉他走向四十歲 ♪
♪ I'm headed down 40 With my old guitar... ♪
什麼鬼
Fuck's sake!
他們有監控
They've got CCTV,
所以不管你對著大門做了什麼
so anything you do to that gate,
我們這裏都看得一清二楚
we can see from in here.
我什麼也沒做
I've not done anything to the gate.
你在大門前罵人了
You were effing and blinding at the gate.
把鞋子脫了
Shoes off.
那太好了
Ah, that's so sweet.
沒關係  沒關係
Oh, yeah, that's fine. That's fine.
進來坐下吧
Come in and sit down.
我先掛了  這裏有客人
Yeah, I've got to go. I've got someone here.
可以
Ah. Okay.
榮幸之至  回聊
Pleasure. Speak to you later. Bye.
你好  我是蘇珊娜
Hello! I'm Susannah.
你好  歡迎你過來
Hi. Thanks for coming.
你以前在哪裏工作過
So, um... where have you been working before now?
一直在斯特林嗎  蘿絲琳
She's been up in Stirling. Haven't you, Rose Lynn?
但她不打算回去
But she's no plans to go back.
那地方很漂亮  很壯觀
Oh, it's beautiful up there. Majestic.
是啊
Yeah.
好吧  我要去買東西了
Right, I'm off to spend a penny.
所以工資是一小時12英鎊
So, it's ￡12 an hour.
12嗎  其實瑪麗只有
Twelve? Actually, Mary gets...
八英磅嗎  行
Eight pound? Right,
但是她能承受那麼低的價格
but... she can afford to go that low
因為她也在喝啤酒
because she's on the brew as well.
啤酒嗎  她喝酒嗎
Brew? She drinks?
我想瑪麗不會喝酒  不  不
I don't think Mary drinks. No, no.
啤酒就像是救濟品
The brew is like, you know, the dole.
真的嗎  嗯  是的
Really? Mm, yeah, yeah.
但是我不會做那樣的事
Whereas I'll not be up to anything like that.
只是不是我  知道我的意思嗎
It's just not me. Know what I mean?
別提這件事讓她難堪
Don't embarrass her by mentioning it.
蘇珊娜  你需要更多的漂白劑
Oh, you were needing more bleach, Susannah.
我給你收據
I'll give you the receipt for it.
好的  謝謝
Oh, okay. Thanks.
蘿絲琳
Rose Lynn?
天哪  蘿絲琳  對不起
Oh, Jesus! Rose Lynn? Sorry.
我急著出去
Um, I'm just gonna pop out and...
大約一小時後回來好嗎  可以
I'll be back in about an hour, okay? Okay.
也有可能不用一個小時
Or... or maybe less.
我整天進進出出  不知道什麼時候回來
I'm in and out all day so I don't know when I'll be back. Just...
好吧
Great.
一會兒見
Right, see you in a bit.
♪ 你違背了誓言  如今一切都已結束 ♪
♪ Well, you've broken your vow And it's all over now ♪
♪ 但如果有一天  寶貝你有了薪水 ♪
♪ But someday, baby When you've had your pay ♪
♪ 你會想見媽媽  但她會說 ♪
♪ You're gonna want your mama But your mama will say ♪
♪ 繼續努力 ♪
♪ Keep movin' on ♪
♪ 你已經離開太久了 ♪
♪ You been away too long ♪
♪ 好吧  我一直和你在一起 ♪
♪ Well, I'm through with you It's too bad you're blue ♪
♪ 你的憂傷太糟糕了 ♪
♪ It's too bad you're blue ♪
♪ 我正繼續前行 ♪
♪ I'm movin' on ♪
嘿
Hey!
♪ 那輛大型八輪車駛出賽道 ♪
♪ That big eightwheeler rollin' down the track ♪
♪ 意味著你那真愛老媽不會再回來 ♪
♪ Means your truelovin' mama ain't comin' back ♪
♪ 我正繼續前行 ♪
♪ I'm movin' on ♪
♪ 我很快便會離開 ♪
♪ I'll soon be gone ♪
♪ 你曾為我的小小天空而翱翔天際 ♪
♪ You were flying too high for my little sky... ♪
媽的 該死
Fuck! Jesus! Fuck!
你倆嚇我一跳
Yous gave me a shock.
你們的媽媽呢  正在停車
Where's your mum? Parking the car.
你倆就像閃靈二姐妹一樣
Yous are like something out of The Shining.
什麼是閃靈啊
What's "The Shining"?
好吧  你們要進來嗎
Well, are yous coming in?
這裏面有股酵母味
There's a yeasty smell in here.
什麼味道
What kind of smell is it?
酵母  什麼
Yeasty. What smell?
我不知道  但它確實像
Well, I don't know, but it sure as
某個傻叉烤麵包的味道
hell insane somebody baking bread.
等我一下  別掛電話
Hang on a minute.
她不會再碰火腿而他只吃火腿
She won't touch ham and he won't eat anything but,
他們現在達成共識  都不喜歡酸奶
and they've both now decided they don't like yoghurt.
你有日曆嗎  你需要一個日曆
Have you got a calendar? You need a calendar.
用來記下他們的健身日和假期
For putting down their gym days
以及他們需要加進去的一些安排
and their holidays and if they're needing to bring something in.
十有八九他們不會告訴你
Nine times out of ten they will not tell you,
所以你需要一周檢查一次他們的書包
so you need to go through their bags once a week
並且你需要支付這些
and you need to pay these.
你能做到的  你現在已經得到了一份薪水
You can do it. You've got a wage
你就可以支付安裝費
now and you can pay in instalments.
你的煤氣費  水費和電費
Your gas, your water and your electricity...
還有
and...
你的電視費
your TV licence as well.
好了  你在這設置就行了
Okaysmokey. Well, that's you set up here.
記住 你必須就在這個範圍里
Remember, you have to be in immediate range of that
從晚上七點到早上七點
from 7.00 at night until 7.00 in the morning, okay?
你好
Hello?
你好  打擾一下
Hi? Excuse me?
你好  怎麼了  那是你孩子麼
Hi. Yeah? Is that your wee boy out here?
小林  開門  我是警察
Lyle? Open up, it's the police!
萊爾 萊爾
Lyle? Lyle!
到這兒來
Get in here.
現在立刻
Right now!
我就先走了
Right, that's me away.
你知道我在哪兒
You know where I am...
如果你需要我的話
if you need me.
不  你要待在這兒和你媽媽一起
No, no, you're staying here with your mammy.
不過你每天都可以看到我
But you'll see me every day.
你會每天都看到我的
You'll see me every day.
我要和你一塊兒回家
I'm coming home with you.
不 留在媽媽那裏  現在做個乖孩子
No, you stay with your mammy. Now, be a good boy.
快點  抱著他
Come on, take hold of him now.
抱著他
Take hold of him.
快點啊
Come on.
我想和我奶奶一起走
I want to go with my granny!
不行
No, you don't.
好了  小林
Come on, Lyle.
我不想待在這兒
I don't wanna stay here!
我們週五出去吃晚餐好嗎
See, on Friday, will we go out for our dinner?
我記得你最愛吃的是什麼
I remember what your favourite is.
是披薩
It's pizza.
我喜歡香腸  芝士和西紅柿
I like sausage, cheese, tomato.
她喜歡芝士  西紅柿和芝士
She likes cheese, tomato and cheese.
你要和我們一起嗎
Are you coming with us?
行 我要出去了  好的
Right, that's me away. Okay.
孩子們告訴我你是一個西部鄉村歌手
The kids tell me you're a country and western singer.
你在搞笑嗎
Are you taking the piss?
不不 一點兒也沒有 你為什麼這麼說
No! No, not at all. Why do you say that?
西部鄉村音樂 不 只是鄉村音樂
Country and western? No, it's just country.
我沒意識到
Oh, I didn't realise.
你一定非常棒
You must be very good because all
整一周我聽到的都是蘿絲琳
I've heard all week is "RoseLynn."
為什麼是鄉村音樂
Why country?
因為它只需三根和弦  且真實動人
Cause it's three chords and the truth.
三根和弦唱真實
哇
Wow.
並且它像這樣  能將心中所思盡數表達
And it goes like that, just gets whatever's in there out.
我們下周再見了
Anyways, I'll see you next week.
非常感謝  拜
Thanks very much. Bye.
拜
Bye.
好的  謝謝
All right. Thanks.
抱歉  你先過
Oh, sorry. After you.
他就是個蠢貨
Him, that fucking prick.
見鬼  不好意思
Shit. Sorry, mate. Fuck.
出去  媽的
Get out! Fuck.
抱歉  對不住  小心點
Oh, sorry, pal. Sorry. Watch yourself.
別擔心  我很好
Ah, don't worry about it. It's fine.
戴維  我沒事
I'm all right, Davey.
那是我  你這白癡
That's me. You fucking idiot!
不不不  我剛剛摔倒在地上了
No, no, no. I just fell on the floor.
你去哪  我的宵禁時間到了
Where you going? I've got my curfew.
別擔心什麼宵禁  別走了
Never mind the curfew. Come on, stay.
喝我的  留下來吧
Drink mine. Stay. Oi!
媽的
Fuck!
你好  這裏是戈爾韋的屠戶
Hello. Galloways the butcher's.
我能為你做些什麼
What can I get you?
我在和你鬧著玩 和你開玩笑呢
Yeah, I'm playing with you. I'm only kidding you on.
沒錯
Aye, yeah,
我是蘿絲琳·哈倫
RoseLynn Harlan.
我在這兒
I'm here.
好吧  拜
All right, okay, bye.
披薩是怎麼回事
Oh... What happened to pizza?
你不能承諾他們某事然後就玩失蹤
You cannot promise them something and then just disappear.
你不可以這麼做  我沒玩失蹤
You cannot do that. I didnot disappear.
我當時在工作  在等我的薪水
I was at my work, waiting on my wages.
蘿絲琳  你不可能騙過所有人的
Please! You're not fooling anybody, RoseLynn.
你也不能這樣騙我
And you cannot fool me.
你告訴他們一件事  不能背棄承諾
See, you tell them something, you don't go back on it.
這是基本的
That's basic.
這是最基本的
吃披薩去  快來
Right, pizza. Come on.
可你不喜歡披薩
You don't like pizza.
我會吃些別的
I'll have something else.
♪ 蒙哥馬利的約翰·普林·安吉爾 ♪
♪ John Prine Angel From Montgomery ♪
♪ 我是個老女人 ♪
♪ I am an old woman ♪
♪ 以我母親的名字命名 ♪
♪ Named after my mother ♪
♪ 我的老伴是另一個 ♪
♪ My old man is another ♪
♪ 年歲漸長的孩子 ♪
♪ child That's grown old ♪
♪ 如果說夢想如同雷鳴 ♪
♪ If dreams were thunder ♪
♪ 那麼閃電便是慾望 ♪
♪ And lightning was desire ♪
♪ 這棟老房子很久以前就該被燒燬 ♪
♪ This old house would have burnt down a long time ago ♪
♪ 讓我變成飛出蒙哥馬利的天使 ♪
♪ Make me an angel That flies from Montgomery ♪
♪ 讓我變成一張宣傳海報 ♪
♪ Make me a poster... ♪
♪ 蒙哥馬利的約翰·普林·安吉爾 ♪
♪ Kitty Wells It Wasn't God Who Made Honky Tonk Angels ♪
♪ 生活之狂野 ♪
♪ ...wild side of life ♪
♪ 當我聽到你的言語 ♪
♪ As I listen to the words you are saying ♪
凱蒂·威爾斯  她是個先驅者
Kitty Wells! What a trailblazer.
自你週五離開
I've been listening to this stuff since
我就一直在聽這首歌  不能自已
you left on Friday and I can't stop.
這是意外之喜  一會兒見
It's a revelation. See you in a bit.
♪ 並非上帝創造了那些低級的天使 ♪
♪ It wasn't God who made honkytonk angels ♪
♪ 就如你歌中所言 ♪
♪ As you said in the words of your song ♪
請進
Come in.
你知道嗎  我剛才在想
You know, I was um... I was just thinking,
我可以給你一些我的建議
I could give you some recommendations.
比較堅強的那種
Like, strong women and all that.
我喜歡那種  我愛聽你唱歌
Oh, I'd love that. I'd love that. I'd love to hear you sing.
你在哪唱歌 是那種有場景的嗎
Where do you sing? Is there, um... Is there a scene?
不不不  這他媽全胡扯
Oh, no, no. No, there's fuckall here.
事實上這就是我
It's actually what I'm...
我其實想去納什維爾
I'm actually trying to get to Nashville. Oh.
需要籌集幾千英鎊
I'm needing to raise a couple of
這樣我才能搞定機票和酒店
grand so I can get flights and a hotel.
我不會開車  所以也需要一個司機
I cannot drive, so I'm needing a driver as well.
不會多於兩三千  肯定不到五千
It wouldnot be more than two or three, definitely less than five.
蘿絲琳  我吧
RoseLynn, I...
很抱歉  我不能就這麼給你錢
I'm sorry, I can't just give you money,
如果這就是你所建議的事
if that's what you're suggesting.
我確定這不是  不這就是我的建議
I'm sure it wasn't. No, it was.
我不能這麼做  怎麼不行
I can't do that. How no'?
我沒有開玩笑  但我就是在想
I'm not being funny, but I just thought
你並不會因此而失去所有的
with all the smelly candles burning everywhere
那些到處燃燒的香薰蠟燭和瓶裝水什麼的
and bottled water and all that, you wouldnae miss it.
在我攢夠之前我會變老  無人問津
I'll be old and grey before I've saved up, whereas you...
我的意思是  你可以甘於平淡
I mean, yous could just drink out of the tap.
別在意了
Anyways, never mind.
你到底在做什麼
What are you actually doing...
攢錢準備離開嗎
while you're waiting, saving to go?
自我14歲以來
I've been the star fucking attraction at
老子就是格拉斯哥大劇院的明星
Glasgow's Grand Ole Opry since I was 14.
然後呢  然後什麼
And? And what?
沒什麼了
Nothing.
你為什麼沒去參加電視選秀節目
Why haven't you gone in for one of those TV talent shows?
那不適合會唱歌的人
They're no' for folk who can sing.
其存在是為了那些想要坐下來
They're for folk who want to sit in
邊吃著咖喱邊看電視的人
with their saag aloo and watch the telly.
去見那些可以讓你飛黃騰達的人
Isn't it a way of meeting someone here
難道不是一種辦法嗎
who can introduce you to someone there?
這兒沒有懂行的人
There's nobody here.
這就是我要離開的原因
That's why I'm away.
整個英國沒有一個人
No one in the whole of Britain
能懂鄉村音樂嗎
knows anything about country music?
除了我  除了你
Except me. Except you?
對  還有鮑勃·哈里斯
Yeah. And Bob Harris.
那是誰
Who's that?
他是BBC二套的主播
Well, he's a DJ at BBC Radio 2.
純傳說中的男人  傳統的小哥
Pure legend, man. Ancient wee guy.
他對鄉村音樂無所不知
He knows everything about country
所有的明星都是他兄弟
music. All the stars, they're his pals.
那太棒了
That's great.
你就該給他寫封信
That's who you need to write to.
這個想法不錯
Aye, yeah, it's good thinking. I'll
我現在就去他家附近狂轟亂炸
just away and pop round his house!
不行  我做不到
No, I cannae do this.
為什麼不行  因為我覺得自己很蠢
Why not? 'Cause I feel like a fanny.
好了  你們兩個出去待著
Okay, you two, go on outside.
別這樣  快點 就十分鐘
No! Yes, ten minutes.
我們出去也是在門外偷聽
All we're gonna do is listen outside the door.
沒事的
It's... it's fine. It's fine. It's cool.
你確定嗎  對  沒關係
You sure? Yeah, yeah. Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
♪ 孩子  關掉電視吧 ♪
♪ Hey, kids, turn off the TV ♪
♪ 我不想看晚間新聞 ♪
♪ No, I don't wanna watch the evening news ♪
♪ 所以到這兒來 ♪
♪ So come on over here ♪
♪ 坐在我的身旁 ♪
♪ Sit down next to me ♪
♪ 讓你媽媽好好看看 ♪
♪ And let your mama look at you ♪
♪ 看看你們 看看你們 ♪
♪ And you and you ♪
♪ 你們那一張張漂亮的臉蛋 ♪
♪ Your beautiful faces ♪
♪ 讓我想要守護你們 ♪
♪ That I wanna keep safe ♪
♪ 直到海枯石爛 ♪
♪ As long as I can ♪
♪ 這是我現在要對你們說的話 ♪
♪ I'm telling you right now ♪
♪ 這棟房子將會和諧安寧 ♪
♪ There's gonna be peace in this house ♪
♪ 會縈繞著溫柔的交談聲 ♪
♪ Gonna be some tender talking ♪
♪ 還有一些甜蜜的隻言片語 ♪
♪ And some sweet little nothings that ♪
♪ 組成我們生活中不可或缺的東西 ♪
♪ Add up to the somethings we can't live without ♪
♪ 這棟房子將會和諧安寧 ♪
♪ There's gonna be peace in this house ♪
♪ 有一些信仰在這所房子裏 ♪
♪ Some belief in this house ♪
♪ 所有曾發生的幸福的事情 ♪
♪ Every good thing that ever happens ♪
♪ 皆始於此 ♪
♪ Happens from the inside out ♪
♪ 我正要告訴你們啊 ♪
♪ I'm telling you now ♪
♪ 這兒將會和諧安寧 ♪
♪ There's gonna be peace ♪
天哪  太棒了
Goodness! Amazing!
留下來吃晚餐吧  不了  謝謝你
Want to stay for dinner? Oh, no, thank you.
謝謝
Thanks.
所以你住在哪兒 蘿絲琳
So, where do you stay, RoseLynn?
牧師山
Priesthill.
在伯魯克路  沒錯
Ah, Pollok way. Aye, yeah.
薩姆老家在克萊德班克  克萊德班克嗎
Sam's from Clydebank. Clydebank?
克萊德班克：蘇格蘭城市，是大格拉斯哥地區的衛星城
你是怎麼從克萊德班克來到這兒的
How did you get here from Clydebank,
直接從窗戶闖進來嗎
break in through a window?
起初和我爸學著做生意  後來我就自己幹了
Learned a trade from my father and then I started up on my own.
什麼生意
Aye? What trade?
溫室
Conservatories?
就是那種周圍用玻璃罩著的房子嗎
Is that the big glass things stuck on the side of houses?
我沒想要開玩笑
I'm no' being funny,
不過在格拉斯哥誰會需要溫室呢
but who needs a conservatory in Glasgow?
你肯定想不到  你說得沒錯
You'd be surprised. Oh, aye, I would be.
你在找什麼呢  平板電腦
What are you looking for? iPad.
媽媽同意你玩嗎  不同意
Did Mum say you can have it? No?
那就不行  我跟你說  跟我去踢球才好玩
No. Tell you what, let's go play some football, eh?
你越來越重了
Oh, you're getting heavy, boy.
蘿絲琳  你想要孩子嗎  想的呀
Do you want kids, RoseLynn? Aye, yeah.
不過不是現在
Just not yet.
今天在學校怎麼樣
How was school today?
帕特太太還在那兒當老師嗎
Is Mrs Pat still there?
她以前特別討厭我
Oh, she hated me, Mrs Pat.
麥當勞小姐還是你最喜歡的老師嗎
Is Miss McDonald still your favourite?
她不在那兒了
Miss McDonald left.
你餓了嗎  嗯
You hungry? Mmhmm.
我收到一封郵件
I've got something.
親愛的蘇珊娜  好久沒聯繫了
"Dear Susannah, so wonderful to
很高興收到你的消息
hear from you after all this time.
我把你的郵件轉給了莉茲
I passed your email on to Liz.
你還記得她嗎  以前經常在水槽裏尿尿那個"
Remember Liz used to piss in the sink?"
她在《今日》節目組工作
She, um... Oh, she works on the Today programme
她又把鏈接轉給了
and she sent the link to her husband
她在第二套當體育播音員的老公
who covers sport for Radio 2
最後他把鏈接轉給了鮑勃·哈里斯的製作人
and he forwarded the link to Bob Harris's producer.
天吶
Oh, my God!
我沒在做夢吧  還有
Oh, my fucking God! Wait.
如果她想來倫敦現場
"Bob would be very happy to meet her
看一次錄音的話
if she fancied coming down to London
鮑勃會很高興和她見面的
to watch a live recording."
你知道我給這個小混賬寫過多少信嗎
Do you know how many times I've written to that wee bastard
每一次我都只會收到一支BBC鉛筆
and how many BBC pens I got back in return?
我靠  你到底是怎麼辦到的
How did you do that? How did you even fucking do that?
就發了幾封郵件而已  簡直了
Sent a few emails. I cannae be...
我簡直不敢相信  我都激動得發抖了
I cannot believe it. I'm fucking shaking.
我都不知道該說什麼了
That is just... Oh.
謝謝你  太感謝了  我簡直要瘋掉了
Thank you, thank you. That is fucking mental. Brilliant!
你是說鮑勃·哈里斯
Bob Harris?
那個耳畔低語者鮑勃·哈里斯
Whispering Bob Harris?
沒錯
Aye.
BBC第二電台 ♪
♪ BBC Radio 2 ♪
我明白  這簡直太讓人難以置信了
Aye, I know, I know. It's mad.
他可以給你帶來很多機會
That would be some doors he could open for you.
麻煩您臨時照看下孩子方便嗎
Is... Is it all right if you babysit?
她當然沒問題
Oh, of course she will.
這是誰搞定的  蘇珊娜
How did this come about? Susannah.
有她幫你真是太好了
Oh. Very nice of her to help you.
她能把案底也抹掉嘛
Can she unlock tags as well?
你曾經因為試圖走私一包海洛因
You served 12 months
在克恩頓谷監獄坐過1年牢
for attempting to smuggle a package of heroin into Cornton Vale
克恩頓谷監獄：位於蘇格蘭的一座女子監獄
你當時直接把毒品從圍牆扔進去
by throwing it over the perimeter fence.
我根本不知道那個是海洛因
I didn't know it was heroin.
那你也太草率了
But you were reckless as to what the package contained.
如果你是想問我是不是醉到
If you mean, was I off my face and
連包裏裝的什麼都沒問的話  是的
didn't ask what was in it, then aye.
我有運貨的馬車  他們給了我監獄地址
I had wains and everything and they give me the jail.
確實很荒唐
Pure ridiculous.
我的律師當時已經說過了  這不是我的錯
That's what my advocate said at the time... it's not my fault.
那是誰的錯
Well, whose fault was it?
明顯是法官的錯  看他的判決就知道了
Well, it was the judge's, obviously, for giving me the sentence.
法官大人
Your Lordship,
我的委託人對自己所做的事深表悔意
a more contrite young lady it would be hard to find.
哈倫女士進行了深刻的自我反省
Ms Harlan has done a lot of soulsearching.
非常非常深刻
She has... dug deep.
那些魯莽幼稚的行為已經成為過去
And she's put her childish ways behind her.
她現在跟普通的女性一樣  有全職工作
She now works fulltime as a daily woman
她的孩子們也回到她的身邊了
and her children are living with her once again.
雖然哈倫女士已經不在監獄裏了
Though Ms Harlan is no longer in prison,
但她並不自由
neither is she free.
綁著這樣一個裝置意味著
Wearing a tag means she is unable to seek employment
她沒法在自己的行業裏找到好工作
in her own line of work.
你剛說她就是普通的上班族  是的
You just told me she's a daily woman. Yes.
但是請您翻到下一頁
But if you turn the page, sir...
您會看到我的委託人
you'll see my client is also
同時也是一位大有前途的西部鄉村歌手
a promising young country and western singer.
我的老天  別亂說
Oh, for God's sake.
只是鄉村  沒有西部
It's just "country."
法官大人  如果我的委託人要開始新的生活
My lord, this young lady must be allowed out in the evenings
她必須被獲准晚上出行
if she is to make a new start.
我回來了
Yeah!
你不是在宵禁中嗎  跟我的律師說去吧
You are barred. You can take that up with my lawyer
給他來一杯威士忌可樂
who'll be having a whisky and Coke.
嘿  沒聽到剛才我說什麼嗎
Oi, you! Oi, you, what did I just say?
她還在宵禁
She's barred!
準備演奏《法外之心》
Outlaw State Of Mind!
傑克  看好她
Jack, tell her! ♪ ...in no time at all... ♪
別在這兒丟人現眼了  搞什麼鳥
Go back to your mice! What is this? What the fuck?
快讓她下來
Stop that, will you?
簡直是亂搞  快停下你的波普爵士
This is a joke! Off you bop.
女士們  先生們
Ladies and gentlemen,
下面有請蘿絲琳·哈倫
RoseLynn Harlan! Whoo!
燥起來  臭娘們
Come on! You bitch!
♪ 在爸爸的舊木吉他上留下齒痕 ♪
♪ Cut my teeth on Daddy's old LGO ♪
♪ 在新墨西哥州的某個地方我失去理智 ♪
♪ And I lost my mind Somewhere in New Mexico ♪
♪ TW在我的背上刻下蛇形紋身 ♪
♪ And TW put a snake on my back ♪
♪ 一旁我開了一家紅色的酒吧 ♪
♪ I keep a red bar on my side ♪
♪ 這片土地上所有的人們 ♪
♪ And there's people all across the land ♪
♪ 從肯塔基東邊一直到阿拉巴馬 ♪
♪ From East Kentucky down to Alabama ♪
♪ 整日跟我一樣 ♪
♪ Whole lot like I am all the time ♪
♪ 都有著法外之心 ♪
♪ I'm in an outlaw state of mind ♪
格拉斯哥萬歲
Come on, Glasgow!
♪ 我的朋友們知道如何尋歡作樂 ♪
♪ I got friends who know How to have a good time ♪
♪ 他們喝著卡羅萊納的烈酒盡情搖擺 ♪
♪ Yeah, they roll their own Drinking Carolina shine ♪
♪ 我看見了黑暗煤礦中惡魔 ♪
♪ I've seen the devil In a dark coal mine ♪
♪ 佐治亞的松樹也沒我高 ♪
♪ I've been higher than a Georgia pine ♪
♪ 這片土地上所有的人們 ♪
♪ And there's people all across the land ♪
♪ 從肯塔基西邊一直到格蘭德河 ♪
♪ From West Kentucky down the Rio Grande ♪
♪ 什麼都不在乎 ♪
♪ Just don't give a damn ♪
♪ 自始至終 ♪
♪ All the time ♪
♪ 我有著法外之心 ♪
♪ I'm in an outlaw state of mind ♪
快過來
Come on!
不好意思  情不自禁
Sorry, sorry.
♪ 這片土地上所有的人們 ♪
♪ There's people all across the land ♪
♪ 從紐約一直到舊金山 ♪
♪ From New York down to old San Fran ♪
♪ 什麼都不在乎 ♪
♪ Who just don't give a damn ♪
♪ 我有著一顆 ♪
♪ Oh, I'm in an outlaw state of ♪
♪ 法外之心 ♪
♪ Mind ♪
太感謝了
Oh, thank you very much.
居然是一等座  我希望你不會
First class! I hope you're not
有我能把這個錢還你的奢望
expecting me to give you money for that.
你還是一如既往的有禮貌
Ah, gracious as ever.
拿著這些錢  以備不時之需
There you go, just in case.
天吶
Oh... Oh!
真的太感謝你了
Thank you, thank you!
靠  我他媽的終於出遠門了
Fuck, fuck. This is fucking me off the fucking blocks!
我一回來就來找你
Right. I'll see you when I come back.
好的
Yeah!
再見
Bye, bye.
感謝各位乘客搭乘維珍列車
We'd like to welcome passengers travelling with us today
我們的列車從格拉斯哥中央車站出發
from Glasgow Central.
這個火車好棒啊  你吃過早餐了嗎
That's good, isn't it? You get your breakfast.
真可愛啊你  沒事別太擔心了
You're lovely. You're fine. Don't you worry about it.
他在女生旁邊會緊張得出汗  閉嘴吧你
He sweats around girls. Shut up!
烤麵包  茶  還有培根卷  全都是免費的
Free toast and tea. Free bacon rolls
但是根本沒人碰
and nobody's touching it.
聽上去不錯  太浪費了
That's not bad, is it? It's a waste.
你們想來點兒嗎  我去弄點
Do you want one? Here, I'll get you one. My shout.
培根卷  培根卷  培根卷
Bacon rolls, bacon rolls, bacon rolls!
Bacon rolls, bacon rolls, bacon rolls
快上車吧
Jump in.
回吧  祝你好運
Go on, go! Good luck.
再會
See you! Bye!
你看到我的包了嗎
You seen my bag?
什麼  我把包放這兒了
Sorry? I left my bag here.
我把包和外套放座位上了
I left my bag and my jacket on this seat.
你應該是拿著走的
Um, I think you took it with you.
不  我沒拿  我就把它們放在這兒的
No, I didn't take it with me. I left
沒道理不見了
it here. It cannot just disappear.
有人過來拿走了我的東西嗎
Did...? Did anyone come and take it?
媽的
Shit.
這怎麼可能不是你們的責任
How is it not your responsibility?
我現在只剩下這兩樣東西了
'Cause this is all I've got now.
耳機和這個  你告訴我
That and these. Just tell me. Tell
我現在能做什麼
me, what is it I'm meant to do?
我們徹底檢查過車廂了  確實沒有
The train was thoroughly checked
也沒有任何東西被交到失物招領處
and nothing's been handed in.
你最好聯繫交警
You might be best talking to the transport police
先拿一個報案號
and getting a crime reference number.
你沒事兒吧
Are you okay?
需要給誰打電話嗎
Do you need to phone someone?
我只是想幫她而已
I'm only trying to help her.
抱歉  我有急事
Sorry! Excuse me!
不好意思  我有急事
Sorry. Sorry, mate.
我想去BBC
Hi, I'm looking for the B... I'm looking for the BBC.
你只需要乘坐地鐵到
Right, okay, you'll need to take the Tube down to...
你沒明白  我現在沒錢
What? No, I don't have any mon...
請問你知道BBC怎麼走嗎
Do you know where the BBC is?
我靠  總算到了
Oh, thank fucking God!
你好  我叫蘿絲琳·哈倫
Hi. RoseLynn Harlan.
您找誰  鮑勃·哈里斯
Who are you here to see? Bob Harris.
您帶著身份證之類的嗎  沒有
Have you got any ID? No.
我來的路上有個雜種偷了我的包
No, some bastard stole my bag on the way here,
所以我現在什麼都沒有
so no.
我知道了  我需要您現在登個記
Right. I'm gonna need you to sign in.
什麼  你們這兒是軍情五處嗎
What, is it MI5 here?
警察局都沒你們這麼麻煩
Jeez, they give you less hassle in the police station.
你是蘿絲琳嗎  我是
Are you RoseLynn? Aye.
你好  我是馬克·鮑勃的製作人
Hello. I'm Mark, Bob's producer.
老天  見到你真是太好了
Oh, jeez, it's so good to see you, boy.
沒事兒  你現在已經在這兒了
You got here, then?
是的
Aye, I did.
從這兒穿過去就是錄音棚
So, the studio is through here,
這兒是控制室
and... round here is our control room
鮑勃·哈里斯就在控制室裏
and in the control room is Bob Harris.
你就是蘿絲琳吧  我簡直不敢相信真的是你
You must be RoseLynn. I cannae believe it's you. Oh!
我對天發誓  我本以為你是個矮小的老頭
Honest to God, I thought you'd be tiny wee.
這就是米蘭達·蘭伯特她們演奏的地方嗎
Oh, is that where they go, Miranda Lambert and all that?
米蘭達·蘭伯特: 美國鄉村音樂創作型女歌手，曾經連續六張專輯登頂公告牌鄉村專輯榜
來這兒的歌手都是在那演唱嗎  沒錯
All they folk who come in here? It is, yeah.
一會兒還會有一個超棒的歌手在這兒演出
And we've got someone fabulous playing later.
你想一起看嗎
Would you like to have a look around?
和一個我們本土的鄉村音樂明星見面真是令人興奮
So, this is very exciting, meeting a homegrown country star.
從格拉斯哥來  那可是個偉大的音樂之都
From Glasgow! I mean, it's a great music city, Glasgow.
是嗎  其實我想要去納什維爾的
Oh, yeah? I'm trying to get to Nashville, obviously, but...
有誰聽說過格拉斯哥出過鄉村樂歌手呢
I mean, who's ever heard of a country singer from Glasgow?
聽上去就很荒謬  完全不可能
That's ridiculous. It cannot be.
為什麼不可能
Why not?
你知道嗎  我這一生就像一個變性人一樣
See my life? My life's like being one of these transsexuals.
你知道嗎  就是那種生下來是男人
You know? When you're born a man, but
但是卻想成為一個姑娘的人
you were meant to come out a lassie.
我就是這樣的人  我應該生在美國
Yeah, that is me. I should have been born in America.
我應該是個美國人  結果我卻在這裏
I'm an American, but here I am.
你會寫歌嗎  不會
Do you write? Oh, no.
樂器呢  也不會
Can you play? No.
老實說  我認為你來自什麼地方並不重要
Honestly, I don't think it matters
蘇格蘭也好  肯塔基也好
whether you're from Glasgow, Scotland or Glasgow, Kentucky
重要的是你的聲音和你想表達的東西
if you've got a voice and you've got something to say.
我看了你的鏈接  毫無疑問你有副好嗓子
I watched your link, and you really do have a voice.
你需要想想自己想表達的是什麼
So, what do you need to say?
♪ 不要把時間浪費在那把吉他上 ♪
♪ Don't waste your life on that guitar ♪
♪ 離開但別走遠 ♪
♪ You may get gone But you won't get far ♪
♪ 不是最初 ♪
♪ You're not the first ♪
♪ 也不會是最終 ♪
♪ You won't be the last ♪
♪ 你可以向我們傾訴 ♪
♪ You can tell us all about it ♪
♪ 當你落魄而歸時 ♪
♪ When you come crawling back ♪
♪ 你走的那條路 ♪
♪ That road you're on ♪
♪ 風雨飄搖 ♪
♪ Just winds and winds ♪
♪ 你在原地打轉 ♪
♪ You're spinning your wheels ♪
♪ 浪費時間 ♪
♪ You're wasting your time ♪
♪ 舞檯燈光亮起 ♪
♪ When the lights come up ♪
♪ 我聽到樂隊奏樂 ♪
♪ And I hear the band ♪
♪ 他們說我從未有過自知之明 ♪
♪ Where they said I'd never be Is exactly where I am ♪
♪ 我聽見人群喧囂 ♪
♪ When I hear the crowd ♪
♪ 回顧四周座無虛席 ♪
♪ I look around And I can't find an empty chair ♪
♪ 無處可去的女孩覺得不賴 ♪
♪ Not bad for a girl going nowhere ♪
你沒有鑰匙嗎
Have you no keys?
你的包和夾克哪去了
Where's your bag and your jacket?
蘇珊娜剛從車站把我接回來
Susannah just picked me up from the station just now.
我落在她車後座了
I left it on her back seat.
很棒啊  是的
Was it good? Aye.
倫敦怎麼樣
What like was it? London.
簡直胡扯  瑪麗這麼說的
It was hoaching. Oh, that's what Mary said.
她去看了好幾次她侄子
She's been down a couple of times to see her nephew.
說你不能推別人
Says you can't move for people.
說真的  不管到哪都是人擠人
Honest to God, wherever you go people are up your nose,
接踵摩肩的那種
in your mouth, under your nails.
我真受不了
I couldn't stand that.
鮑勃怎麼樣
What was he like? Bob.
我覺得他
I think he was...
他說我得創作自己的曲子
He was saying I'm needing to write my own tunes.
我要寫些什麼呢  寫漂白劑和掃帚私奔麼
What am I gonnae write about? The bleach ran away with the broom?
你做事沒有毅力
You don't stick at things.
你知道嗎  那是你的短板
You know, that's your trouble.
但看看這所房子
But look at this house.
當你下定決心時
When you put your mind to something...
則事竟成
you can do anything.
要喝杯茶嗎  不不  我要睡覺了
Do you want a cup of tea? Oh, no. I'm away to my bed.
我明天還要早起
I'm up early the morrow.
但你可以請我吃晚飯
But you can ask me for my dinner.
小林跟我講他喜歡你做的肉末和馬鈴薯
Lyle's telling me how he likes your mince and tatties
他不喜歡我做的
and he doesnae like mine.
我沒有肉餡
I don't have a mince.
我做的肉末其實是你做的
My mince is your mince.
晚安
Night.
我吵醒你了嗎  沒有
Did I wake you up? No.
我想喝點水
I wanted some water.
你的書講了什麼
What's your book about?
一個小女孩和她的狗狗的故事
About a girl and her dog.
聽起來對你來說有點幼稚
That sounds a bit babyish for you.
第二個關鍵階段
Key Stage 2.
你幹嘛那麼做
Why are you doing that?
我不知道
I don't know.
來  我帶你去睡覺
Here, I'll take you back to bed.
很漂亮  是給誰的
Those are nice. Who are they for?
這個給伊斯拉  這個給索娜
This one's for Isla and this one's for Shona.
伊斯拉和索娜
Isla and Shona.
你的期中假快到了  你知道嗎
Yous have halfterm coming up. Do you know that?
你有一整個星期的假
You have a whole week off school.
我們做什麼好呢
What will we do, eh?
我們會離開幾天  去沙灘
We'll go away for a few days, to the beach.
我還沒去過沙灘  不  你去過的
I've not went to the beach. Yeah, you have.
你當時太小了所以不記得
You're too young to remember.
我們當時在
We went just before...
在你搬去和你奶奶住之前
just before yous moved in with your granny.
你當時想把貝殼都撿起來  記得嗎
You wanted to pick up all the shells. Remember that?
我們為什麼不能見你
How come we weren't allowed to see you?
因為你奶奶不想讓你進監獄
'Cause your granny didn't want you coming to the jail.
誰還會養你呢
Who else was gonna bring you?
是因為你是壞人嗎
'Cause of baddies?
但是你不是壞人  你是個逃犯
You weren't a baddie, though. You were an outlaw.
誰跟你說的  你自己
Who told you that? You did.
不  我不是逃犯
No, I wasn't an outlaw.
我是個妓女
I was a fanny.
你說了妓女
You said fanny!
怎麼樣  我給你打了無數次電話
How was it? I tried calling you so many times.
我知道  我手機丟了
Oh, I know. I lost my phone.
天哪  發生什麼事了
No! What happened?
其實它被偷了  真的嗎
Actually, it got pinched. Oh, really?
是的  從我的包裏  拿著我的包
Yeah, out of my bag, with my bag.
臥槽  不重要了
Crap. Didn't matter.
太他媽棒了  真的嗎
It was fucking A! Was it?
真的嗎
Really?
我要去那  我他媽要去那了
I'm gonna get there. I am gonna fucking get there.
你當然要
Yes, you bloody are.
聽著  怎麼了
Listen. Yeah?
我就快五十了
I'm gonna be 50 in a minute and...
我為此要舉辦我一直不感冒的酒會
I was gonna have this drinks party for which I've got very little enthusiasm for.
因為這個週末我意識到
'Cause over the weekend I realised
我需要的是一個真正的聚會
what I really need is a "party" party,
一場盛大的戶外派對
a great big fuckoff house party,
比如  邀請一位前途似錦的鄉村歌手
featuring, say, a set by... a young upandcoming country singer,
蘿絲琳·哈倫
RoseLynn Harlan.
什麼鬼  你想讓我到你的派對上表演
What? You want me to play at your party?
真的  你願意嗎
Yeah. Will you?
太好了  那真是太讚了
Well, aye, yeah, course I will. That is brilliant.
這一點不令人興奮
That is not the exciting bit.
最激動的是  相比於送禮物
The exciting bit is, instead of bringing gifts,
人們對你的事業起到幫助
people will contribute to a cause
更合我心意
that is very close to my heart... you.
你表演一組
You perform a set.
如果大家喜歡你的表演  他們就會
If people like what they hear, which they will,
然後他們投資你  投資你的事業
then they invest in you, in your career.
就像  一百個人贊助五十到一百英鎊
That's, like, a hundred people spending between ￡50 and ￡100.
完美
Voila.
通過眾籌的力量  你會到那
By the magic of crowdfunding, you are there.
哪兒  馬恩島
Where? The Isle of Man.
納什維爾
Nashville!
你為了一個天天跟你呆在一塊的女人
What, you're gonna tax your pals to come to your house
就要向你來看表演的朋友收費
for an audience with your daily woman?
對
Yeah.
你的詭計失敗了  長舌婦
You've lost the plot, hen!
對了  你有樂隊嗎  當然有
Oh, do you have a band? Aye, yeah, course I do.
什麼時候  下週日
When is it? Next Sunday.
你已經請了一周的假了
You've already booked the week off,
你可以用來排練
and you can use that time to rehearse.
天哪  不行  這周沒空  但是
Oh, no. No, I can't do that week. But
這很周到  但我不需要排練
it's cool, I don't need to rehearse.
我從十四歲就和他們一起表演了
I've been playing with these guys since I was 14.
你絕對需要排練  蘿絲琳
RoseLynn, you definitely need to rehearse.
如果你想讓那些人掏錢
If you're asking people for money, if...
如果你想讓別人
If you want people to buy in to the
給你即將實現的理想出資
idea that you're gonna make it out there,
那你就得表現得很專業
then you need to put in a really professional performance.
對哦  沒錯  太他媽棒了
Oh, yeah, cool, yeah. FuckingA.
棒極了
Brilliant.
我挑不出刺來
Well... I can't fault it.
媽
Mum?
蘇珊娜下周找我有事  她不能這麼做
Susannah's needing me in next week. She cannae have you.
孩子們在放假  她沒有你撐得過一周
Kids are on holiday. She can do without you for a week.
你說會把他們帶走
You said you'd take them away.
嗯  不是
Well, it's no', uh... it's no'
不是要大掃除  是要排練
cleaning I'd be doing, it's rehearsing.
我在她家裏演出
I'm doing this gig at her house.
她邀請了所有人
She's invited all these people
我要和樂隊一起表演
and I'm gonna perform with my band.
然後他們會投資
And then they're gonna invest.
投資  投資什麼
Invest? Invest in what?
投資我  我的事業
In me, in my career,
去納什維爾
in getting to Nashville.
我可不記得她在瑪麗
I don't remember her investing in Mary
被髖骨疼痛所困擾時投資過她
when she was in agony with her hip.
18個月長的等待名單呢
Eighteenmonth waiting list.
如果她有餘錢的話  她本可以照顧一下
If she'd money to spare, she could have forked out on that.
她不是在給我錢
She isn't forking it out.
她是給了我一個機會去賺錢
She's giving me a chance to earn it.
一定要成功  不是那種酒吧樂隊
But it's got to be good, no pub band.
我們很久沒有聚在一塊了
We haven't long to put it together.
我打電話給學校
I phoned the school to see about
看看有沒有假期俱樂部  但都滿員了
holiday club, but it's all full up,
況且我寧願他們跟你呆在一塊
and I'd rather they were with you
我不想讓他們覺得
'cause I don't want them thinking...
覺得什麼
Thinking what?
當你得到更好的報價後  就拋棄他們
That you cast them off when you get a better offer?
或者根本就是無緣無故的
Or that all this is for nothing 'cause
因為你覺得你依然可以隨時抽身而去
you've still got one foot out the door?
我沒法幫你
I can't help you.
我沒有預約休息時間
I haven't booked the time off.
你在那裏已經20年了
You've been there 20 year.
特殊情況  我用得夠多了
Special circumstances. I've used that enough.
是的  當我搞砸的時候
Aye, when I was fucking up.
你可不能不勞而獲
What's for you will no' go by you.
我是努力為自己做點事情
This is me trying to make something of myself.
當然是為了他們好
Surely to God that's a good thing for them.
為他們好
A good thing for them?
別再讓他們一次又一次失望了
No' letting them down again and again and again,
那才是為了他們好
that would be a good thing for them.
我還以為你回心轉意了
And I thought you'd turned a corner.
別再把我當傻子
More fool me!
我們去哪  我們要去沙灘
Where are we going? We're going to the beach.
我們要去海裏  看看不同的水母
We're going to go into the sea and look at different jellyfish.
來  乖寶寶  來
Come on. That's a good boy. Come on.
我們到了
Here we go.
進來吧
Oh, in yous come.
我不想進去
I don't want to go in there!
瑪麗這周來照顧你們  好不好
Mary's gonna look after you for a wee while this week, okay?
我沒說一星期  我說是一天  蘿絲琳
I didn't say a week, RoseLynn, I said today.
你很棒  你很棒
Oh, you're fine, you're fine.
來吧  媽媽會回來的  你很棒
Come on. Mum'll be back. You'll be fine.
♪ 我從未卑躬屈膝  也從未藐視界限 ♪
♪ Well, I never did crawl And I never did toe the line ♪
不行  這  這樣太慢了
Ah, no. Come on, this is... It's way too slow.
♪ 我從未卑躬屈膝  也從未藐視界限 ♪
♪ Well, I never did crawl And I never did toe the line ♪
♪ 我的事情自己做主 ♪
♪ No man is master of me I ain't that kind ♪
♪ 穿上旅鞋 ♪
♪ I just put on my travelling shoes ♪
♪ 若你想贏 ♪
♪ If you want to win ♪
♪ 就別揮霍光陰 ♪
♪ You just can't lose the time ♪
♪ 也別畏縮不前 ♪
♪ Or stay behind ♪
♪ 我生而為戰 ♪
♪ Well, I was born to run ♪
♪ 領先他人 ♪
♪ To get ahead of the rest... ♪
♪ 只為無可匹敵 ♪
♪ And all that I wanted was to be the best ♪
♪ 只為自由而戰 ♪
♪ Just to feel free ♪
媽媽
Mum!
♪ 功成名就 ♪
♪ And be someone ♪
♪ 生而敏捷  生而為戰 ♪
♪ I was born to be fast I was born to run... ♪
謝謝了  阿曼達  沒關係  沒關係
Thanks, Amanda. Oh, nae bother, nae bother.
你以前認識我  不是嗎
Yous know me from old, don't yous?
我們可以玩個遊戲  經營旅館
We can play a wee game... hotels.
你們來當服務員  我當客人
You can be the waiter and waitress and I'll be the guest.
晚上見  好嗎
See yous later, okay?
我討厭你
I hate you!
好啦  進來吧
Right, come on.
♪ 感覺很好 ♪
♪ ...makes you feel all right ♪
♪ 我生而為戰 ♪
♪ Well, I was born to run ♪
♪ 領先他人 ♪
♪ To get ahead of the rest ♪
♪ 只為無可匹敵 ♪
♪ And all I wanted was to be the best ♪
♪ 只為自由而戰 ♪
♪ Just to feel free ♪
♪ 出人頭地 ♪
♪ And be someone ♪
♪ 我生而馳騁  生而追逐 ♪
♪ I was born to be fast I was born to run ♪
♪ 生而追逐 ♪
♪ I was born to run ♪
♪ 傲視群小 ♪
♪ To get ahead of the rest ♪
♪ 我想要的只有極致 ♪
♪ And all I wanted was to be the best ♪
♪ 只為無拘無束 ♪
♪ Just to feel free ♪
♪ 出人頭地 ♪
♪ And be someone ♪
♪ 我生而馳騁  生而追逐 ♪
♪ I was born to be fast I was born to run ♪
耶  好多了
Yeah! That was much better.
哇  這女人還看上了誰
Wow, who else has this lassie invested in?
洛·史都華
Rod Stewart?
洛·史都華：曾是世界上最出色的搖滾歌手之一
好了  確實準備了很長時間
Right, now, it's been a long time,
但我真的很喜歡一張通告表通通搞定
but I do love a call sheet.
如果明天下午四點你們都在這兒
So, if you could all be here from 4.00 tomorrow,
我們就四點半進行聲音調試
then we'll run sound check from 4.30,
之後  適應燈光提示
and after that... we'll go to the lighting cues.
明天可是個大日子  先生們
Big day tomorrow, gents.
姑娘我連最後一層地板都給你們弄乾淨了
This girl has cleaned her last floor.
放著我來  你沒必要做這個
Leave it. You don't have to do that.
不  沒什麼的  我只是
No, it's all right. I'll just...
我只是把它們移進去
I'll just pop them inside.
我從技術人員那兒搞到的
I nicked it from the tech guys.
來一支
Fancy a smoke?
噢  不  我該  我該走了
Oh, no, I've... I've got to go.
真的  是的
Really? Yeah.
你會捲煙嗎
Can you roll it?
我第一次遇到薩姆時
When I first met Sam,
我們住在克萊德賽德最狗屎的
we lived in this shittiest
小公寓裏
little flat on Clydeside.
那時我們一無所有  不像現在
There was nothing there, not like it is now.
因為臨河  總有許多老鼠
We had rats because of the river,
基本一個星期就有一次入室盜竊案
we were broken into nearly once a week,
但我們舉辦了那些非常棒非常棒的派對
but we had these really, really amazing parties.
不是很想抽了
Don't really want this.
你在戀愛嗎
Do you have someone?
不  我自由得像只小鳥
No, I'm... free as a bird.
真幸運
Lucky you.
你還年輕
You're young.
你天賦異稟  又正值精力巔峰
You're incredibly talented. You're at the height of your powers.
沒有什麼是你做不到的
There is nothing you can't do.
把握好機會
This is your time.
一旦你有了孩子  情況就不一樣了
Once you've got kids, it's a little bit different.
是的
Yeah.
我該走了
I'd better go.
你好
Hello?
怎麼樣  甜心  我很好  謝謝
How are you, honey? I'm fine, thank you.
我送你  不了  你人真好
I'll drop you home. Oh, no, you're all right.
沒事的  我乘公交就好
It's fine. I'll just take the bus.
來吧  不
Come on. No
好好休息  好的
Sleep well. Aye, yeah.
明早見
See you in the morning.
你很想家嗎
You homesick, aye?
什麼  這是你泡妞
What, is this the one where you
睡妹子的地方嗎
try and stick it up the daily woman?
不  不
No, no.
這是我揭穿你的地方
This is the one where I tell you that I'm on to you.
我知道你坐過牢
I know you did the jail.
我也知道你是為什麼進去的
And I know what you were in for.
不管你在兜售什麼  蘇珊娜
Susannah's bought into whatever it is you're selling,
都吃你這套  我也不想掃她的興
and I'm not about to take that away from her now.
但我不想你接近我的孩子分毫  所以
But I don't want you anywhere near my kids, so...
明天見
See the morrow?
你唱你的歌  拿你的錢
Sing your song, get your money,
然後消失
then you're gone.
小林  跟上
Lyle, hurry up.
我們可沒有一整天的時間
We haven't got all day.
蘿茜  你去哪了  兄弟
Rosie! Where you been, man?
完全不見蹤影啊
Havenae seen hide nor hair of you.
好吧  小不點呢  我一會兒進來
All right, wee man? I'll be in in a minute.
你還好吧  夥計
You all right, pal?
很好  你知道的  我改過自新了
Aye, you know, I'm brandnew.
小林
Lyle?
他叫小林  五歲了
His name's Lyle. He's five.
他搖晃衣櫃時衣櫃翻倒壓在他身上
He swung on a wardrobe and it fell on him.
我想應該只是手臂受傷
I think it's just his arms that he's
但頭可能也傷到了
hurt, but maybe his head as well.
好的  小林  介意我稍微看看嗎
Okay, Lyle, do you mind if I have a wee look?
沒事的  她只是稍微檢查一下  好嗎
All right. She's gonna have a wee look, okay?
對什麼過敏嗎
Any allergies?
不  我不  我認為沒有
No, I don't... I don't think so, no.
織物類創可貼
Fabric plasters.
好的  嗯  他需要照個X光
Okay, um, we'll need to Xray him.
今晚病人比較多
It's one of those nights some here,
所以你們可能要過一段時間才能等到醫生
so it might be a while until a doctor sees yous.
好的  我要外婆
Okay. I want my granny.
安靜  安靜  我要外婆
Shh, shh... Please! I want my granny!
沒事的  沒事的  我要外婆
It's okay, it's okay. I want my granny!
你是小林的媽媽嗎  我是
Are you Lyle's mum? Aye, yeah.
我是尤薩夫醫生  抱歉等這麼久
Dr Yousaf. I'm sorry about the wait.
沒關係
No.
X光顯示沒有大問題  但需要打個石膏
The Xray looks fairly straightforward, but he'll need a cast.
我們什麼時候可以回家
When can we go home?
腫脹消退後才可以安石膏
We can't get the cast on until the swelling's come down,
所以要再觀察幾個小時
so we are looking at a couple more hours.
很抱歉今晚這麼折騰
I'm sorry it's been such a long night.
媽的
Oh, fucking hell.
6個未接來電
他在哪  他還在睡覺
Where is he? He's still asleep.
好吧  我把這個帶回家
Right. I'll take this one home and
你留在這兒陪小不點
you can stay here with the wee fella.
不
No.
你那樣的生活安穩得不值得一過
What's for you will no' go by you.
也許在麵包店待20年對你來說已經足夠
Maybe 20 year in the baker's is enough
但我不滿足
for you, but it's not enough for me.
去給我倒杯茶  親愛的
Away and get me a wee cup of tea, darling.
你出什麼毛病了
What's the matter with you?
我只是  我只是想讓你幫
I just... I just need you to help.
幫幫我
Help me.
幫你  幫你做什麼
Help you? Help you do what?
讓你去派對而把他留在這兒  是這樣嗎
Leave him here while you go to a party? Is that the plan?
我不知道那位貴太太把你當成什麼
I don't know what this awf'y toffy woman thinks you are,
但要是她知道了真相  你什麼也得不到
but she wouldnae give you a brass farthing if she knew the truth.
你還沒告訴她  對吧
You havenae even told her, have you?
她連你有孩子了都一無所知
She doesnae even have a clue that you've got kids.
如果你到現在還不打算把他們當回事
If you're no' even prepared to acknowledge their existence,
你就徹底沒救了
there's no hope for you.
對於他們也是一樣
And there's sure as hell none for them.
走吧  去納什維爾
Go. Go to Nashville.
去做你想做的一切  來  親愛的
Do whatever it is you wanna do. Come on, darling.
我們去看看你的小兄弟
Let's go see your wee brother.
♪ 我走進這間酒吧 ♪
♪ Well, I only came into this bar ♪
♪ 只是為了聽一首悲傷的曲子 ♪
♪ To hear a sad song... ♪
♪ 我不想和你在電話裏交談 ♪
♪ I couldn't get you on the phone ♪
♪ 所以我讓它那樣響著 ♪
♪ So I let it ring ♪
♪ 響了又響 ♪
♪ On and on ♪
♪ 在一首孤獨的小夜曲裏 ♪
♪ In a lonesome serenade ♪
♪ 或許我應該嘗試找個方法 ♪
♪ Maybe I should try to find a way ♪
♪ 一點點地  解決它 ♪
♪ To kinda, sorta, maybe work it out ♪
蘿絲琳  你去哪了
Rose Lynn! Where have you been?
上帝啊  我以為你放我鴿子了
Jesus Christ! I thought you were a noshow.
這聒噪地都讓我下不來台了
The band have had to talk me off a ledge.
你看起來很疲憊  你還好嗎
You look tired. Are you all right?
是的  我感到  煥然一新
Oh, yeah, aye. I'm... brandnew.
那就好  那就好
Oh, good, good. Great.
來吧  我們走  你可把我嚇慘了
Come on, let's go. You gave me such a fright.
♪ 兩桶威士忌 ♪
♪ And a doublebarrel whisky... ♪
好
Okay, um...
不久前  我家門前閃光一現
so, not long ago, a spark of light flew in through my door
讓我知道我為什麼
and reminded me of why I fell in
會對格拉斯哥這座城市一見鍾情
love with Glasgow in the first place.
這個女孩  如同這座城市  不可思議
The girl, like the city, is gallus.
她很有趣  更重要的是她無所畏懼
She's funny and, above all else, she's completely fearless.
在你們的幫助下  她會去到納什維爾
And with your help, she's going to Nashville
去做她生而注定的事
to do what she was put on this earth to do.
我很榮幸認識她  並成為她的朋友
I'm so proud to know her and call her my friend.
女士們  先生們
Ladies and gentlemen, put your
請為羅斯·林·哈蘭鼓掌歡呼吧
hands together for RoseLynn Harlan!
好了嗎  開始吧
Okay? Let's go.
不  不好意思  可以給我
Sorsorsorry. Can you just give me...?
給我  給我五分鐘嗎
Give me... give me five.
出什麼事了
What's wrong?
蘿絲琳
Rose Lynn?
嘿  嘿
Hey? Hey!
蘿絲琳  等一等
Rose Lynn, please.
發生什麼了  你在幹嘛  你要去哪
What's going on? What are you doing? Where are you going?
發生什麼了
What's happened?
噢  親愛的  怎麼了
Oh, darling. Come on.
我不知道當你將目光投向我時
I don't know what... what you see
你看到的  是不是我
when you look at me, but it isnae me.
你在說什麼  我不處於什麼巔峰期
What are you talking about? I'm not at the height of my powers.
我也不是無拘無束  有太多
I'm not free and there's so,
太多羈絆我的事情
so much I can't undo.
我坐過牢
I can't undo going to the jail.
我無法忘記  向同我一樣無知的少女
I cannae undo chucking in heroin
去販賣海洛因  醉生夢死
to all they lasses in there already fucked from drugs.
你知道還有什麼嗎
And do you know what else I cannae undo?
兩個孩子
Having two kids.
十八歲以前我生了兩個可愛的孩子
Two beautiful children before I was 18.
薇諾娜八歲
Wynonna, she's eight,
小林五歲  而我
and Lyle, he's five, and I...
我蹲了十二個月監獄  對他們不聞不問
I got 12 months in the jail and I left behind two kids.
是的  那才是真相
Yeah, that's the truth.
而不是你面前的這些
Not this.
一樁樁  一件件
That, them.
所有我給你造成的錯覺
Everything I made you think I am...
都是假象
I'm not.
對不起  我只是
Sorry, I'm just...
來
Come on.
我看到那邊有一個島  一個島
I see an island over there. An island?
是個蛤蜊  你覺得你能打開它嗎
It's a clam. Do you think you can open it?
致力於幫助他人  給每一個人帶去溫暖
哈倫女士
Miss Harlan?
我的意思是  我會開心起來的  只是
I mean, I'll be happy just...
好吧  那就
All right, then.
♪ 祝你生日快樂 ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
要許個願嗎
Did you make a wish?
你幫我許吧
You can have mine.
好了  第一份誰要
Right. Who's having the first slice, eh?
我  好的
Me. Yeah? Good.
國家賽事
六月八日至2012年四月
格拉斯哥  英國
我一個人  嗨
It's only me. Hi.
你有時間嗎
Have you got a wee minute?
有啊
Aye, yeah.
你給過我一些東西了
You already gave me something.
這是用來幹嘛的
What's this for?
你為什麼給我這個
Why are you giving me this?
我想讓你負起責任
I wanted you to take responsibility,
但我從未想過要剝奪你的希望
but I never meant to take away your hope.
我不知道你在說什麼
I don't know what you're talking about.
生活可能有更多的可能性  可能沒有
Maybe there is more to life or maybe there isnae.
我不知道
I don't know.
我到過最遠的地方就是杜恩
I've never been further than Dunoon.
但你應該出去看看
But you need to away and see.
不
No.
我無法重新來過
I cannae start all that up again.
一切都結束了
It's finished.
我總是說如果我不用十五歲就開始工作
I always said I'd go to college
我會去上大學的
if I hadnae had to go to work at 15.
或者我本就會去
And I would have.
我曾想做一名藥劑師
I wanted to be a pharmacist.
實際上
The thing is...
你知道是什麼阻止了我嗎
what was stopping me, you know?
在我生了你以後  我本可以去的
Even after I had you, I could have gone.
但我想為你著想  總比
But I think it was just easier for me to...
總比為自己拚搏
to want things for you
要容易的多
than to go after them for myself.
我沒有那份勇氣
I hadnae the gumption.
我承認
That's the truth.
但你
But you...
你有
you do.
我會照顧好孩子們
I'll look after the wains.
放心去吧
You go.
你知道等待著你的是什麼
You see what's waiting for you.
這錢從哪裏湊的呢
Where did you get all this money from?
在烘焙店干了20年
Amazing what you can do...
這點積蓄還是有的
20 year in the baker's.
♪ 不要害怕擦破膝蓋 ♪
♪ Don't be afraid to graze your knees ♪
♪ 大膽越過籬笆 ♪
♪ Jump over the fences ♪
♪ 爬上樹 ♪
♪ Climb up trees ♪
♪ 人們笑對黃粱一夢 ♪
♪ Folk, they will say don't fly too high ♪
♪ 但奮鬥總會實現 ♪
♪ But put on those wings And reach for the sky ♪
♪ 起點錯了也別擔心 ♪
♪ And it's all right to be all wrong ♪
♪ 要知道越挫越勇 ♪
♪ You've got to be weak If you wanna be strong ♪
♪ 去跳自己的舞蹈吧 ♪
♪ So dance your own dance ♪
♪ 唱自己的歌吧 ♪
♪ Sing your own song ♪
♪ 過夢寐以求的生活 ♪
♪ And live the life you dreamed of ♪
左轉彎距孟菲斯和查塔努加1英里  直行1英里到納什維爾
♪ 直到夢想實現 ♪
♪ Till the dreamer is gone ♪
雷曼教堂展覽
市中心約翰尼·卡什博物館
德雷克汽車旅館
就停這吧
Great.
給你錢  非常感謝  居住愉快
There you go. Thanks very much. Have a great stay.
謝謝
Thank you.
你在鎮上待多久呢
How long are you in town?
我不清楚
Oh, I don't know.
不知道  走一步看一步吧
I don't know. It just... Well, it depends what happens, you know, so...
好吧  我希望你都能如願以償
Well, I wish you what I wish all y'all who come here...
願你所有的傷心事都能成為歌
may all your heartbreaks be songs
並且你所有的歌都能成為熱門
and all your songs be hits.
借你吉言  左轉第三個房間就是
Thanks! Third door on the left.
酷
Whoo!
♪ 五點響起自由的哨聲 ♪
♪ Well, there's five o'clock freedom And the whistle would blow ♪
♪ 如水閘破裂後的 ♪
♪ Gates would burst open
♪ 河水涌出之勢 ♪
The river would flow ♪
♪ 那夜晚些去了舞廳 ♪
♪ Later that night shifts To the dance halls... ♪
♪ 我在失去本心 ♪
♪ I'm missing my roots ♪
♪ 也在擺脫過去浮華 ♪
♪ I'm getting rid of the fire ♪
♪ 無人需要千元衣服 ♪
♪ Nobody needs a $1,000 suit ♪
♪ 就為了去扔垃圾 ♪
♪ Just to take out the trash ♪
♪ 不必獨自一人 ♪
♪ Ain't gotta be alone... ♪
你知道如何才能在那唱歌嗎
How do you get to sing?
你得去登記啊
You gotta go through our booker.
那裏有等待名單  所有信息都在網站上
There's a wait list. It's all on the website.
但如果我只是做臨時的酒吧歌手呢
But what if I'm only here for a while.
這裏有來自各國的人
There's people here from all over,
如澳大利亞  新西蘭  德國
from... Australia, New Zealand, Germany.
我們所有人都在做相同的事情
We're all trying to do the same thing.
這是納什維爾  商業小鎮
You know, it's Nashville. It's a company town.
所以最後你會遇到認識某個
So eventually you're gonna meet someone who knows somebody
在某個地方工作可以幫助你的人
who works someplace who can help you out.
你需要什麼嗎  不需要  謝謝
Can I get you something? No, I'm fine, thanks.
歡迎來到鄉村音樂主母教堂  雷曼教堂
Welcome to the Ryman, the mother church of country music.
藍草：鄉村音樂分支
這是藍草音樂誕生的地方
This is the exact spot where bluegrass was born
並且也是約翰尼·卡什
and where Johnny Cash
約翰尼·卡什：美國鄉村音樂創作歌手，多次格萊美獎獲得者
邂逅瓊·卡特的地方
met June Carter.
瓊·卡特：美國著名鄉村音樂作者和歌手 約翰尼·卡什的妻子
正是在這裏  鄉村音樂在它自己後門
Now, it was right here that country music found an audience
找到了聽眾
beyond its own back porch
數不清的職業也誕生了
and countless careers took off.
大劇院：位於美國納什維爾市的大劇院劇院素有美國鄉村樂靈魂的美譽
現在看到的是當大劇院
Now, when the Grand Ole Opry
1943年在這裏落地生根時
put down roots here in 1943,
直播的廣播和電視節目捧火了譬如
the live radio and TV show brought the likes of
以下提到的這些人名均為為美國鄉村音樂發展出做過貢獻的歌手和演員
埃爾維斯·普雷斯利
Elvis Presley,
漢克·威廉姆斯
Hank Williams,
約翰尼·卡什
Johnny Cash,
馬蒂·羅賓斯
Marty Robbins,
米妮·珀爾
Minnie Pearl,
佩西·克萊恩
Patsy Cline,
和羅伊·阿庫夫這類的明星
and Roy Acuff
也將他們的唱片帶到了美國人的客廳裏
to the stage and into living rooms all around America.
♪ 當我到了 ♪
♪ When I reach ♪
♪ 我要去的地方 ♪
♪ The place I'm going ♪
♪ 我定會知道我的路 ♪
♪ I will surely know my way ♪
♪ 我會回頭 ♪
♪ And I will turn ♪
♪ 審視內心 ♪
♪ And look inside me ♪
♪ 一天天向過去告別 ♪
♪ And bid farewell to one more day ♪
♪ 之後我會飛躍 ♪
♪ I will fly ♪
♪ 這山谷 ♪
♪ Beyond this valley ♪
♪ 打開希望之門 ♪
♪ I will open up the gates ♪
♪ 就會到了 ♪
♪ And when I reach ♪
♪ 我要去的地方 ♪
♪ The place I'm going ♪
♪ 我定會知道我的路 ♪
♪ I will surely know my way ♪
♪ 我生來 ♪
♪ I was born
♪ 就沒有聽過耳語 ♪
Without a whisper ♪
♪ 我生在雨中 ♪
♪ I was born beneath the rain ♪
♪ 當我到了 ♪
♪ And when I reach ♪
♪ 我要去的地方 ♪
♪ The place I'm going ♪
♪ 我定會知道我的路 ♪
♪ I will surely know my way... ♪
你絕不會相信有多少人這麼做
You would not believe how many people do that.
外地的麼  給老懷亞特一張紙幣
On the tour? Give old Wyatt the slip,
在那舞台上站著  也能唱首破歌
get up there, sing a whole damn song.
是的，我以為那個小迪斯尼小子會打電話給城邦
Aye, I thought that wee Disney prick was gonna call the polis.
我完全不知道你在說什麼
I have no idea what you just said.
但聽好了  我要從週六開始
But look, I'm getting drinks a week
和我朋友勞蕾爾喝一星期的酒
from Saturday with my buddy Laurel.
她是柯布唱片公司的員工
She's some kind of deal at Curb Records.
如果你想見她  可以來餐廳
So, if you wanted to meet her, you could come by the restaurant.
不了  謝謝  不過
No, no. Thanks, but...
我回去了
I'm away.
♪ 寶貝  當我到了 ♪
♪ And when I reach ♪
♪ 我要去的地方 ♪
♪ The place I'm going, babe ♪
♪ 我定會知道我的路 ♪
♪ I will surely know my way... ♪
已經放棄了嗎  不是
Quitting already? No.
並沒有  我才剛開始
No, I'm just kicking off.
麻煩去機場
Airport, please.
♪ 我們能抑制悲傷 ♪
♪ We have hands to hold our sorrow ♪
♪ 用眼淚治癒傷痛 ♪
♪ We have tears to heal the pain ♪
♪ 即使眼中透露疑問 ♪
♪ And though your eyes Ask many questions ♪
♪ 但卻在喊我的名字 ♪
♪ On your lips I hear my name ♪
♪ 我生來 ♪
♪ I was born
♪ 就沒有聽過耳語 ♪
Without a whisper ♪
♪ 我生在雨中 ♪
♪ I was born beneath the rain ♪
♪ 當我到了所想之地 ♪
♪ But when I reach the place I'm going ♪
♪ 我定會知道我的路 ♪
♪ I will surely know my way ♪
媽咪
Mum!
天吶 你都長這麼高了嗎
Oh, God, look at you, eh?
看看你
Look at you!
媽咪 你回來了  是啊
Mummy, you're back. I'm back!
我回來了  你想我了嗎  想
I'm back! Did you miss me? Yes.
有多想呢  一千萬個想嗎
Yeah? How much? Ten million?
是的
Yeah.
你們有替我照顧你們的外婆嗎
Have yours been looking after your granny for me?
就像你們聽到的這樣 我不是納什維爾人
Uh, as you can hear, I'm no' from Nashville.
一年後
我來自格拉斯哥
I'm from right here in Glasgow! Whoohoo!
格拉斯哥：蘇格蘭一城市  如今是蘇格蘭最大的城市也是一個重要商業和文化中心
這是我自己編的曲
Er, well, this is a... a tune that I wrote.
老實說  若你們能聽到三個和弦
You'll be lucky if you get three chords
就會很幸運的
out of me, honest to God!
無論怎樣  我要開始了
Anyway, I'll give it a go.
♪ 我已磨壞 ♪
♪ I've worn out the stones ♪
♪ 你門前的石頭 ♪
♪ In front of your doorstep ♪
♪ 人來人往 ♪
♪ Coming and going ♪
♪ 你點亮了希望之燈 ♪
♪ You left the lights on ♪
♪ 我早就知道 ♪
♪ I always knew that ♪
♪ 我應該謝謝你 ♪
♪ I should have said thank you ♪
♪ 早在一千英里前 ♪
♪ A thousand miles ago ♪
♪ 但我推開了你 ♪
♪ But I pushed you away ♪
♪ 把圖釘按在地圖上 ♪
♪ Put a pin in a map ♪
♪ 然後迷失在風暴中 ♪
♪ Then I got lost in the storm ♪
♪ 必須找尋前進方向 ♪
♪ Had to find my own way ♪
♪ 犯了錯誤 ♪
♪ Make my own mistakes ♪
♪ 但你知道我得前進 ♪
♪ But you know that I had to go ♪
♪ 再沒有了幸運路 ♪
♪ Ain't no yellow brick road ♪
♪ 穿越格拉斯哥 ♪
♪ Running through Glasgow ♪
♪ 但我找到一個 ♪
♪ But I've found one
♪ 比石頭更結實的東西 ♪
That's stronger than stone ♪
♪ 那就是家 ♪
♪ Ain't no place like home ♪
♪ 月光落在 ♪
♪ Moon hanging low ♪
♪ 我的窗上 ♪
♪ Over my window ♪
♪ 鞋盒的夢想 ♪
♪ Shoebox of dreams ♪
♪ 藏於我床下 ♪
♪ Hid under my bed ♪
♪ 跟著明光 ♪
♪ Follow the bright lights ♪
♪ 前往黃金城 ♪
♪ City of gold ♪
♪ 我離開了才知道 ♪
♪ I had to leave to realise ♪
♪ 我需要的在這裏 ♪
♪ All I needed was here ♪
♪ 媽媽  我們都知道 ♪
♪ Mama, we both know
♪ 那什麼都沒有 ♪
That there's nothing ♪
♪ 有段時間帕西蒂·克蘭都不火 ♪
♪ That a little time. And Patsy Cline wouldn't fix ♪
♪ 必須找尋自己的路 ♪
♪ Had to find my own way ♪
♪ 犯了錯誤 ♪
♪ Make my own mistakes ♪
♪ 也得繼續向前 ♪
♪ But you know that I had to go ♪
♪ 再沒有了幸運路 ♪
♪ Ain't no yellow brick road ♪
♪ 穿越格拉斯哥 ♪
♪ Running through Glasgow ♪
♪ 找到了一個 ♪
♪ But I've found one
♪ 比石頭更結實的東西 ♪
That's stronger than stone ♪
♪ 那就是家 ♪
♪ Ain't no place like home ♪
♪ 讓鞋跟發出 ♪
♪ I'll just click my heels ♪
♪ 三聲卡噠聲 ♪
♪ Three more times ♪
♪ 一切都在那裏 ♪
♪ There it all is ♪
♪ 都在我的家裏 ♪
♪ What's always been mine ♪
♪ 沒有了幸運路 ♪
♪ Ain't no yellow brick road ♪
♪ 穿越格拉斯哥 ♪
♪ Running through Glasgow ♪
♪ 我找到了比石頭 ♪
♪ But I've found one
♪ 還堅硬之物 ♪
That's stronger than stone ♪
♪ 那就是家啊 ♪
♪ Ain't no place like home ♪
♪ 就是遮風擋雨的家 ♪
♪ 就是我的家 ♪
♪ Ain't no place like home ♪
♪ 他穿著德州燕尾服 ♪
♪ He wore a Texas tuxedo
♪ 她穿著極品綠牛仔 ♪
She wore Cadillac green ♪
♪ 他們像火柴和汽油 ♪
♪ They went together Like a match and gasoline ♪
♪ 屠宰場的戴維·坎貝爾 ♪
♪ Big Davey Campbell from the abattoir ♪
♪ 在勞倫斯頓酒吧工作的 ♪
♪ And Annie O'Malley
♪ 安妮·奧馬利在勞裏斯頓酒吧工作 ♪
Annie O'Malley
Works the Laurieston bar ♪
♪ 田納西州以東四千英里 ♪
♪ 4,000 miles east of Tennessee
♪ 是要去的佩斯利西路 ♪
Paisley Road West is the place to be ♪
♪ 他曾是牛仔之王 ♪
♪ He was a king of the cowboys ♪
♪ 偷天換日是常事 ♪
♪ Stealing the night ♪
♪ 她是孟菲斯女首領 ♪
♪ She was a queen of Memphis ♪
♪ 以搶銀行為生 ♪
♪ Robbing the bank of life ♪
♪ 搶銀行是她的生計 ♪
♪ Whoaoh, robbing the bank of life ♪
♪ 兩杯威士忌 ♪
♪ Two shots of whisky
♪ 和一杯愛爾蘭啤酒 ♪
and an IrnBru ♪
♪ 舉起手來呀 ♪
♪ Hands up! ♪
♪ 不許動啊 ♪
♪ No one move! ♪
♪ 牛仔之王 ♪
♪ King of the cowboys ♪
♪ 來大搶劫了 ♪
♪ Stealing the night ♪
♪ 孟菲斯王后 ♪
♪ Queen of Memphis ♪
♪ 來搶銀行了 ♪
♪ Robbing the bank of life ♪
♪ 牛仔之王 ♪
♪ King of the cowboys ♪
♪ 大洗劫了 ♪
♪ Stealing the night ♪
♪ 孟菲斯女王 ♪
♪ Queen of Memphis ♪
♪ 搶銀行了啊 ♪
♪ Robbing the bank of life ♪
♪ 穿上應該穿的 ♪
♪ Wear this, don't wear that
♪ 別亂跑啊 ♪
Don't step out of place ♪
♪ 笑一笑  別說太多 ♪
♪ Just smile, don't say too much
♪ 化好妝就行 ♪
Put that makeup on your face ♪
♪ 假裝你很開心 ♪
♪ Just keep pretending You're having a good time ♪
♪ 當你站在台上 ♪
♪ 'Cause that's the price of fame
♪ 因為要顧及名譽 ♪
When you're standing in the line ♪
♪ 這裏的景色 ♪
♪ That's the view from here ♪
♪ 就像你只想要啤酒 ♪
♪ It's like champagne and tears ♪
♪ 卻上來香檳和眼淚 ♪
♪ When all you want's a beer ♪
♪ 讓你愛的人坐近 ♪
♪ Keep your loved ones near ♪
♪ 讓你愛的人坐近吧 ♪
♪ Oh, keep your loved ones dear ♪
♪ 因為名流都很怪異 ♪
♪ 'Cause famous folk are weird ♪
♪ 就是這裏的景象啊 ♪
♪ That's the view from here ♪
♪ 這裏的景象啊 ♪
♪ 就是這裏的景象啊 ♪
♪ Oh, that's the view from here ♪
♪ 就像你只想要啤酒 ♪
♪ It's like champagne and tears ♪
♪ 卻上來香檳和眼淚 ♪
♪ When all you want's a beer ♪
♪ 讓你愛的人坐近 ♪
♪ Keep your loved ones near ♪
♪ 讓你愛的人坐近吧 ♪
♪ Oh, keep your loved ones dear ♪
♪ 因為名流都很奇怪 ♪
♪ 'Cause famous folk are weird ♪
♪ 這就是這裏的 ♪
♪ That's the view ♪
♪ 景象啊 ♪
♪ From here ♪